Why would we still be getting NaNs,
为何依然会出现 NaN？
and if we look at the header,
我们来看看标题
you can see that when we compare two to 104,
当我们比较用户 2 和用户 104 时
which is what we are doing in this test here,
也就是这里测试的用户对
we get a NaN value and really we shouldn't be getting
我们获得了 NaN 值 不应该出现 NaN 值的
that because we're only comparing where these things match.
因为我们只是比较匹配的用户对
So therefore, we shouldn't be getting NaNs.
所以不应该出现 NaN
But if you remember back to the correlation coefficient,
下面回忆下之前的相关系数
before and how that's computed,
回想下它的计算流程
because that's what we're using here,
因为我们在这里使用了该相关系数
that might give you some insight into why we would be getting NaNs.
你可能会明白为何出现 NaN
Let's say we look at the movies to analyze for User 2
我们来看看 movies_to_analyze[2]
and movies to analyze for User 104,
和 movies_to_analyze[104]
that's the comparison we're making up here,
也就是在这里
that's where we're getting NaNs.
出现 NaN 的用户对比较
If we look at a set of each of those,
对它们运行 set()
just to make sure we only get unique values back.
这样仅获得唯一值
So I'm just going to call this set 2 and I'll call this set 104
将这个称为 set_2 并将这个称为 set_104
and let's actually just print that really quick.
快速输出结果
Movies to analyze wasn't found.
name ‘movies_to_analyze’ is not defined
Oh, I spelled it wrong, analyze.
哦 这里拼错了 应该是 analyze
You probably all noticed that before I did.
大家可能已经注意到这个拼写错误
So if you look at this,
这些是
this is just a set of the movies that User 104
用户 104 看过的电影
seen and if we do an intersection with set 2,
如果运行 intersection(set_2)
this gives us the movies they've both seen.
将返回他们都看过的电影
So we're getting a NaN when they've both viewed
他们都看过相同的电影时
the same movies and if you think about why that might be
这里却出现了 NaN
in terms of the correlation coefficient,
我们从相关系数的角度思考为何会这样
what might ring a bell is the way that that's computed and that's
想一想相关系数的计算方式
that it looks at the comparison of these observations,
相关系数会查看这些观察值的比较情况
their mean and in the denominator,
看看它们的均值
we're calculating the standard deviation.
在分母中计算标准差
So one way we might get a NaN is if either
出现 NaN 的原因之一是
one of the standard deviations is a zero,
其中一个标准差为 0
then we're dividing by zero in which case we get a NaN,
除以 0 的话 会出现 NaN
we can't divide by zero.
我们不能除以 0
So we can maybe take a look at what the ratings
我们可以查看
actually were for each user on those specific movies.
每位用户对这些电影的具体评分
So if we store this,
将结果存储到变量中
just call them, same_ movs for now.
变量名暂时设为 same_movs
You'll see for User 2,
可以看到 对于用户 2
they all had the same rating and so that means
所有评分都一样
the standard deviation of these is zero.
所以标准差为 0
Therefore when we compute the correlation coefficient,
当我们计算相关系数时
we end up with a zero and the denominator
分母中出现了 0
and that's bad because we'll get a NaN.
这很糟糕 我们将获得 NaN
So, instead of using this similarity metric,
这里不应该使用相似性指标
it might be a better idea to use something like
而是使用欧几里得距离等其他指标
Euclidean distance where we won't get a NaN when we compute this.
这样就不会出现 NaN
Similarly to what we did before when we were
与之前
computing the correlation coefficient,
计算相关系数差不多
we can use a lot of the same stuff.
我们可以使用这里的大部分代码
So I'm just going to copy it and use it over again down here.
我直接将这些代码复制到下面
Instead of computing the correlation coefficient,
我们将计算欧几里得距离
what we actually want to do is compute the Euclidean distance.
而不是相关系数
With a quick Google search,
在 Google 中快速搜索后
I found this nice NumPy way of doing it so that it would be
我找到了这个很方便的 NumPy 方法
fast where we essentially take what's called the Linalg.norm.
我们将使用 linalg.norm()
So if you take the norm, that's the same as computing
计算范数和计算
the Euclidean distance between these two things.
两个事物之间的欧几里得距离是一样的
So let me pick norm of the column associated.
所以计算相关列的范数
Well in this case, it's actually a row associated with User 1.
在这里实际上是与用户 1 相关的行
Take the row associated with User 2,
获取与用户 2 相关的行
take the difference between those two vectors
获取这两个向量之间的差异
and then you compute the norm and that's
然后计算范数
essentially computing the Euclidean distance
实际上就是计算欧几里得距离